字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
I can see it.
我能看到
That's fine.
没事的
I can dodge them if I'm careful.
如果仔细看 我就能躲过他的攻击
With no contact, I can neutralize his weapons.
只要他不打到我 那么他就和没武器一样
-That's it, kid! -You can do it!
-就这样了 小子！ -你可以的！
-That kid can really fight. -He landed a strike on the commander!
-这小子挺能打啊 -他居然打中了指挥官一下！
The swift like him are tenacious!
他这种速度快的最麻烦了！
It's been a while since we saw a good fight!
很久没看到这么精彩的打斗了！
Damn it, I can't cut him.
该死的 我没法砍伤他
-He's wearing chain mail. -I liked this tunic.
-他底下穿着护身铠甲 -我喜欢这个短袍…
My axes don't seem to scare you much.
你不怕我的斧子 是吧？
You have real courage.
还真是有胆量啊
You definitely got that from Thors.
肯定是从托尔兹那里继承来的
You giant bastard.
你个巨型混蛋
How do you know my father?
我父亲怎么了？
Didn't he tell you anything?
你没从他那里听到什么东西吗？
How inconsiderate of him.
真是铁石心肠
I heard he originally came from nobility, a jarl.
我听说他原本是贵族 是个伯爵
That was Helga's side.
那是赫尔加家的事
Thors gained rank by his own swordsmanship.
托尔兹是靠自己的剑术升职的
What?
什么？
Do you wanna learn more?
哦 你想多听点吗？
Do you?
想吗？
If you want to learn more, you'll have to entertain me a bit more.
要是想继续听下去 那你就得再陪我多玩一会儿
All right, Thorfinn?
托尔芬 行吗？
I can entertain you,
我可以陪你玩
but when I'm done, your mouth might not work so well.
但要手下留情不影响你说话 那很难
Well said, kid!
小子 说得好！
When he's done!?
对指挥官手下留情？
Yeah kid, go easy on him!
可别出手太重啊！
What a moron!
真是个白痴！
Is something funny?
很好笑吗？
Thorfinn is a worthy opponent.
托尔芬是我尊重的战士
Do not laugh at him.
别笑他！
Thors was stronger than me.
托尔兹比我更强
Show me that you are truly the son of Thors,
让我看看 你是不是真是托尔兹的儿子
Thorfinn!
托尔芬！
That stupid child.
这个傻孩子
He came to get killed.
他回来就是来死的
What happened to the prince?
王子怎么样了？
Take that side!
嘿 从那个方向走！
Take out his legs!
抓住他的腿！
From that direction!
那个方向！
Close by,
就在旁边
I can hear the cries of war.
我能听到战争的声音
I wish they would stop.
快点停下吧
Have they nothing better to do?
他们难道就没别的事做吗？
Please be quiet.
请安静
I don't want to open my eyes.
我不想睁开我的眼睛
I want to stay asleep.
我想就这么睡着
Just like this.
就这样 永远睡过去
Your Highness.
殿下
Your Highness, Prince Canute.
殿下 克努特王子
Ragnar!
拉格纳！
You're alive!
你还活着…
This is
这
just a dream.
只是个梦吧？
Ragnar.
拉格纳
Yes.
对 我是来告别的
Will you leave
你会留下我
without me?
一个人离开吗？
Are you saying…
你是说
I must live in this world alone?
我必须要一个人活在这个世界上吗？
How am I to continue?
你觉得我能继续活下去吗？
I have…
作为你的教育者
I have failed you
我没能尽职
I treated you not as a jarl,
我没把你当成伯爵来对待
but as a normal child.
而是把你当成普通孩子对待
I raised you
我像个农民养大自己孩子一样抚养你
I did this against His Majesty's wishes.
我知道这不是陛下想要的
Please forgive me.
请原谅我
How is that wrong?!
这有什么过错呢？
You gave me more than my own father, the king!
你给我的才是我想要的 远胜于我的国王父亲给我的！
I didn't want to be born into royalty.
我并不想出生在王室…
If only…
如果…
If only
如果我是你的儿子
things would have been so much better.
那该多好…
Your Highness.
殿下
Hearing that brings me joy, Your Highness.
殿下 听到这个很让我高兴
I love you.
我爱你
There are things you only understand after losing them.
有些东西只有失去后才能真的理解
You have already realized it.
你已经意识到了
-Ragnar. -I am only in your dreams.
-拉格纳… -我不过是出现在你的梦里
-Wait. -The time has come for you to awaken.
-等等… -到你醒过来的时候了…
No, Ragnar.
不 拉格纳
Come back.
回来
Come back!
回来！
Live well, Your Highness.
好好活着 殿下
Ragnar.
拉格纳…
Do not falter! We can take him together!
别害怕！我们一起上！
How are you injuries?
你受伤了吗？
Those men are fighting over who will take possession of you.
那些人在为谁能得到你而打斗
You have become a prize to be won.
你成了赢家的奖赏
As a monk, can you not stop their fighting?
你是个牧师 你不阻止他们打斗吗？
Is there a way to stop them?
有办法阻止他们吗？
If they wish to die, then we should let them.
如果他们想要去死 那么就该让他们去死
I had a dream.
我做了个梦
I dreamt of Ragnar.
我梦到拉格纳了
He was able to say goodbye.
他和我说了再见
He's a sincere man, even in death.
他是个真诚的人 哪怕死了也是
The only person who loved me
唯一一个爱我的人
has now departed from this world.
已经离开这个世界了
That is a great enlightenment.
这是个巨大的启示
But not entirely true.
但也不全是
Was it love that Ragnar felt for you?
拉格纳对你的感情 是爱吗？
For your safety,
他为了保护你
he witnessed the murder of 62 good villagers.
目睹了62个村民被杀
Your Highness,
殿下
what is
爱是什么？
Man, these guys hardly put up a fight.
天哪 这些家伙几乎没反抗
It's hard to find strong opponents.
要遇到真有实力的对手果然很难
We'll never reach Valhalla at this rate.
这样的话 我们永远都进不了瓦尔哈拉
Is the commander still dueling?
指挥官的决斗还在继续吗？
No way. That kid's dead.
不可能 那小子肯定早就死了
Then why are they shouting?
那大家都在兴奋什么？
I'm gonna take a look!
我去看看！
Me, too!
我也去看看！
Hey, what's going on?
嘿 怎么回事？
-Get him! -Commander!
-杀了他！ -指挥官！
-Damn kid! -Don't run away!
-该死的小子！ -别跑啊！
Seriously?
这是真的吗？
The commander…
指挥官…
That kid is ripping him apart!
那小子居然让他招架不了！
That's it, Thorfinn.
不错嘛 托尔芬
There are maybe five men under me who could take you on.
我的人里 大概只有五个人能和你打
He's wearing the same chain mail as before.
他穿着和之前一样的护甲
I must hit his tendons.
攻击他四肢的肌腱会更有效
When I went for his vital in London he caused me pain.
伦敦的时候 攻击他的致命点 反而给我带来更大的打击
The only way to win this is to stop his mobility.
只有让他的动作停下来 才能让这场决斗结束
Although you're certainly strong,
虽然你确实很强
I feel like your skill with the daggers is but average.
但我觉得你用匕首的水平…很一般
There is something missing that would complete you as a warrior.
你要成为一个战士 还缺点东西
In that case, how did you get so cut up?
如果是这样的话 为什么我能让你这么难受？
This is true.
没错
I'm missing something too.
我也缺了点东西
I was hoping I could learn it from you, son of Thors.
我以为我可以从你这里学来的 托尔兹之子
Tell me, Thorfinn.
嘿 托尔芬
What do you think?
你怎么看？
What does it mean to be
当一个真正的战士
a true warrior?
到底意味着什么？
You're asking what love is?
你问我爱是什么？
Are you saying that Ragnar didn't love me?
你是说拉格纳并不爱我？
Yes.
对
Then I have a question for you.
那我要问你
If Ragnar didn't love me,
如果拉格纳不爱我
then who is the person who properly embodies love?
那么那个真正代表着爱的人在哪里？
There's one over there.
那里有一个
See?
看到没？
He has died
他死了
and has become more beautiful than any living being.
但却比任何活物都更美丽
You can call that true love.
你可以把这视为爱本身
He can
他再也不能恨或者偷窃了
He will remain abandoned here,
他会一直被遗弃在这里
and his flesh will provide generously for the beasts and the insects.
他的肉身会给动物和昆虫足够的给养
He'll be exposed to the wind and the rain
他会暴露在风和雨里
without uttering a word of complaint.
一句怨言也没有
Death…
死亡…
completes the human being.
让人类完整
Hey! What's wrong?
嘿！怎么了？
Damn it!
该死的！
You don't know?
你不知道？
Well, don't worry about it. I didn't expect you to.
也没事 我没指望你知道
That's a cheap trick!
这是阴险的诡计！
That's true love?
所以真正的爱
Death?
就是死亡？
Yes.
对
In that case, what would you call those precious feelings
这样的话 那么父母和子女之间 丈夫与妻子之间
between parents and children, husband and wife, and Ragnar and me?
以及拉格纳和我之间 那些可贵的感情又是什么呢？
Discrimination.
区别对待
Flattering kings while whipping slaves is not so different from that.
这和恭维国王却同时又鞭打奴隶 没什么差别
To Ragnar, Your Highness was more precious than anyone else.
对拉格纳而言 殿下你比任何人都更宝贵
He perhaps treasured you more than his own life.
他可能比珍惜自己生命更珍惜你
That
他对你的喜爱
was discrimination.
是区别对待
I see.
我明白了
I understand now.
我现在懂了
It feels like
就好像
a fog has lifted.
眼前忽然明朗了
What?
什么？
Come on!
行了！
I can't believe it!
放弃吧！
Ouch.
好疼
Damn it. It's still too shallow!
该死的 还是太浅了
I understand.
我明白了
This snow…
这雪
is love, isn't it?
是爱 对吧？
That's right.
没错
The sky.
天空…
The sun.
太阳…
The blowing wind.
吹过的风
The trees.
这些树
The mountains.
还有这些山…
Yet.
但是…
It's unbelievable.
这太不可思议了
The world…
这个世界
God's work is so beautiful, and yet…
上帝的作品是那么美 但是…
inside the hearts of men…
人的内心
love does not exist?
根本不存在爱吗？
It is said that the reason we live this way
据说我们这样活着
is because our ancestors long ago disobeyed God
是因为我们的祖先违背了上帝的旨意
and by choice committed
犯了罪
After that, we were
我们
banished from paradise.
被逐出乐园
-What? -Hey!
-什么？ -嘿！
-Where'd he go? -What?
-他去哪儿了？ -什么？
-Hey! -Is that…
-嘿！ -那是…
He sprung off my foot to soften the blow?
他从我的腿上跳开 以柔克刚？
Not bad.
不错嘛
-Over there! -Incredible!
-在那里！ -了不起！
He's dead now!
这下他肯定死了！
That's our commander!
这就是我们的指挥官！
Damn it.
该死的
Have I finally run out of options?
我这下真的没办法了吗？
I think they're done fighting.
战斗似乎结束了
However,
但是
this isn't good.
这不好
He may have lost his sanity.
他失去理智了
Your Highness, you should make your escape.
殿下 你该逃了
Sanity?
理智？
Where are the sane people in this world?
这个世界理智的人都在哪里？
They're all the same.
所有人都一样
All the same.
都一样
All are the same without the knowledge of love.
人人平等 因为没人知道爱是什么
They don't know the meaning of life, the meaning of death,
没人知道生活的意义是什么 没人知道死亡的意义是什么
or even the meaning of their fighting.
他们甚至不知道 他们战斗的意义是什么
Your Highness…
殿下…
Enough.
够了
I am tired of this.
我受够了
Something was lost in exchange for wisdom.
为了得到智慧 有些东西丢了
A most important thing.
那是最重要的东西
That something…
那是
we will never attain as long as we live.
只要我们活着就得不到的东西
We will never attain it.
我们永远也得不到
But despite that,
但尽管如此
we are still asked to pursue it?
我们却还是被要求去追求它？
Father in Heaven!
天父！
Miserable warrior,
这些可怜的战士
you are the furthest away from love.
你们是距离爱最远的人
You were exiled from paradise.
你们被从天国乐园驱逐
To end the suffering of your punishment, is there no other option but to die?
要终结你们因惩罚所受的痛苦 除了死 就别无选择吗？
Is our only option in life to be tested and to endure?
我们人生中唯一的选择 就是被考验 然后忍受吗？
Father in Heaven!
天父！
By your trials, this man's soul cannot be saved!
以你的审判 这个人的灵魂不能得到救赎！
Father,
上帝
I will no longer seek your salvation.
我不再寻求你来救世
If you will not give it to us,
如果你不给我们
then by our own will
那么我们就自己来
we will create another paradise from this land.
我们会在这片土地上 再创造一个天堂
What? Prince?
什么？王子？
The pain!
好疼！
Prince! Are you okay?
王子！你没事吧？
Stop, you fools.
停下 你们这些蠢货
Stop your meaningless quarrel.
不要再无谓地打斗了
Meaningless?
无谓地？
The wound is severe.
他的伤很重
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Damn it.
该死的
I made a mistake.
我犯了个错
Don't move.
别动
Your stomach has been cut.
你的肚子被割伤了
Willibald!
维利巴尔德！
Treat his wounds.
来治他的伤
I will gather the horses.
我去把散开的马集合起来
You there, with me.
你来帮我
Your Highness.
殿下
I have witnessed a miracle.
我看到了一个奇迹
Shut up and treat him.
闭嘴 快来给他治伤
Wait a minute, Prince!
王子 等等！
Where are you going?
你去哪里？
I'm taking you to Thorkell.
我要把你带给托鲁克尔
If I don't, my comrades will…
我不带你去的话 我的伙伴们会…
I am going to Thorkell myself.
我是打算要去托鲁克尔那里
We cannot transport the injured without borrowing a sled from them.
不向他们借雪橇的话 我们没法运这些受伤的人
You cannot do that!
别说胡话！
Why do you think I'm in tatters, you idiot?
你个笨蛋 我受伤是为了什么？
If you go to Thorkell, all this will have no meaning.
如果托鲁克尔抓到你 这一切就都没有意义了
Meaning? Meaning, you say?
意义？你说意义？
A meaning to your fighting?
你们战斗的意义？
There is no meaning to this battle.
这样的战斗是没有意义的
So don't die.
所以别死
You warriors will become my vassals.
你们这些战士 现在是我的属臣了
From now on, I will tell you when to fight.
在必须的时候 我会告诉你们要打谁
I will give meaning to your battles, your lives, and your deaths.
我会让你们的战斗 生命 还有死亡有意义
That is
那是
the duty of a king.
一个国王的责任